<ecopedia icon="Skill Books">
  <summary loc="233">There are two kinds of experience in Eco: Character Experience (gained by food and housing) and Specialty Experience (gained by performing actions in a specialty).</summary>
  <section type="banner" image="experienceecopedia" />
  <section loc="232">As you gain experience in Eco you will be able to unlock new specialties and new abilities within those specialties. There are two types of experience you will gain, Character Experience and Specialty Experience.  Both are increased by your Experience Multiplier.

<b>Character Experience</b>
Character Experience is your background learning rate, how fast you are gaining knowledge and abilities.  It is constantly going up, even when you’re offline.  Each real-day, you will gain Character Experience at the rate of 1 * your experience multiplier.  When you reach a level up, you will gain a new specialty unlock, represented by a star.  Each level up will require more and more character experience to gain, so it is very difficult to have more than a few specialties.

<b>Specialty Experience</b>
Specialty Experience is your skill at a specific ability, and rather than going up constantly, it only goes up when you perform actions related to that specialty, such as crafting or performing labor.  Like Character Experience, it too is multiplied by your Experience Multiplier. Along the left side of the screen, you’ll see icons displaying how much experience you’re gaining when you perform actions, and you can click these to get a closer look at the level ups for that specialty.
Some level ups will allow you to unlock talents, which give specific bonuses related to the skills they’re in.

<b>Experience Multiplier</b>
Your Experience Multiplier (or XP Multiplier) is a personal value representing your health and support system, and it determines how fast you learn new skills.  It is determined as a sum of your [Nutrition] and [Housing|Housing Overview] values.  Because it affects both your character and specialty experience points, you’ll want to keep it as high as possible by eating the nutritious food and having a well-furnished house.

</section>
</ecopedia>